<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2013 First Lastname <your@email.com> -->
<component type="desktop">
 <id>autovala.desktop</id>
 <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
 <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
 <name>Autovala</name>
 <summary>Simplify the creation of Vala projects</summary>
 <description>
  <p>Autovala is a program and a library designed to help in the creation of
projects with Vala and CMake.</p>

  <p>The idea is quite simple: CMake is very powerful, but writting the CMakeLists
files is boring and repetitive. Why not let the computer create them, by
guessing what to do with each file? And if, at the end, there are mistakes,
let the user fix them in an easy way, and generate the final CMakeLists files.</p>

  <p>This is what Autovala does. This process is done in three steps:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>First, Autovala checks all the folders and files, and writes a project
    file with the type of each file</li>
    <li>It also peeks the source files to determine which Vala packages they need,
    and generate automagically that list</li>
    <li>After that (and after allowing the user to check, if (s)he wishes, the
    project file), it uses that project file to generate the needed CMakeLists
    files</li>
  </ul>
  <p>Autovala greatly simplifies the process of working with Vala because:</p>
  <ul>
    <li>Automatically determines the vala packages and libraries needed to compile
    and run the project, by inspecting the source code</li>
    <li>Automatically generates the .vapi and pkg-config files for libraries</li>
    <li>Automatically determinates the final destination for an icon, by checking
    its type (svg or png) and, in the later case, its size.</li>
    <li>Automatically generates manpages from text files in several possible input
    format (markdown, html, latex...).</li>
    <li>Greatly simplifies creating libraries in Vala, or a project with a binary
    that uses a library defined in the same project.</li>
    <li>Automatically generates the metadata files to create .DEB and .RPM packages.</li>
    <li>Easily integrates unitary tests for each binary in the project.</li>
    <li>Can generate automatically DBUS bindings by using the DBUS introspection
    capabilities.</li>
    <li>Automatically generates the list of source files for GETTEXT.</li>
    <li>Simplifies mixing C and Vala source files.</li>
  </ul>
 </description>
 <url type="homepage">http://www.rastersoft.com/programas/autovala.html</url>
 <updatecontact>raster@rastersoft.com</updatecontact>
</component>
